Guide to the Bruce W. Calnek papers, 1947-2001
Calnek, Bruce W. papers, 1947-2001
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Bruce W. Calnek papers, 1947-2001
24-02-3346
Calnek, B. W.
0.3 cubic ft.
Class notes, correspondence, meeting minutes, slides, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The bulk of this collection is correspondence, meeting minutes, slides, and photographs relating to the construction of the Veterinary Medical Center and the Veterinary Education Center at the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine, 1987-1992. There are also class notes taken by Dr. Calnek while he was a DVM student at Cornell. In addition there is information about the S.B. Hitchner Student Scholarship, the Poultry Advisory Council, and the Rudolph J. Steffen Professorship.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Bruce. W. Calnek is an emeritus professor of avian medicine at the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine. He received his DVM from Cornell in 1955, joined the faculty at the College in 1961, and was named chair of the Department of Avian and Aquatic Animal Medicine in 1977. He retained that position until his retirement in 1995. Among his many contributions to the College and the University is his chairmanship of the Central Planning Committee that oversaw planning for the construction of the Veterinary Medical Center and the Veterinary Education Center.
For more information about Dr. Calnek, please consult his oral history interview in the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Oral History Collection, RMC # 24-04-3349.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The bulk of this collection is material relating to the construction of the Veterinary Medical Center and the Veterinary Education Center at the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine, 1987-1992. There are also class notes taken by Dr. Calnek while he was a DVM student at Cornell. In addition there is information about the S.B. Hitchner Student Scholarship, the Poultry Advisory Council, and the Rudolph J. Steffen Professorship.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Calnek, B.W.; Hitchner, Stephen B.; Steffen, Rudolph J.; Cornell University--College of Veterinary Medicine--Buildings
Subjects:
Veterinary Medicine -- Study and teaching.; Veterinary Hospitals--Design and construction.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PROVENANCE
Donated by Dr. Bruce W. Calnek in 2004.
RELATED MATERIAL
Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Oral History Collection, RMC # 24-04-3349.
CONTAINER LIST
- DVM Class Notes - Poultry Diseases, Book 1, Spring 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- DVM Class Notes - Poultry Diseases, Book 2, Spring 1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Hitchner Scholarship, 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Stephen B. Hitchner Biographical Material, 1947-ca. 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Steffen Chair, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Poultry Advisory Council, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Central Planning Committee - Construction Newsletters, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Central Planning Committee - Minutes and Agendas, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Central Planning Committee - Minutes and Agendas, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Central Planning Committee - Minutes and Agendas, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Central Planning Committee - Meeting Schedules, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Construction Slides, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Construction Slides, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Central Planning Committee Photo, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)